Enter the world of fairies
Tinker Bell is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Bradley Raymond.
Journey into the secret world of Pixie Hollow and hear Tinker Bell speak for the very first time as the astonishing
story of Disney's most famous fairy is finally revealed in the all-new motion picture "Tinker Bell."
Tinker Bell (voice), played by Mae Whitman.
Rosetta (voice), played by Kristin Chenoweth.
Iridessa (voice), played by Raven-Symoné.
Silvermist (voice), played by Lucy Liu.
Fawn (voice), played by America Ferrera.
Fairy Mary (voice), played by Jane Horrocks.
Tinker Bell is a 2008 American animated fantasy film and the first installment
in the Disney Fairies franchise produced by Disneytoon Studios.
It is about Tinker Bell, a fairy character created by J.
Barrie in his 1904 play Peter Pan, or The Boy Who Wouldn't Grow Up, and featured in the
1953 Disney animated film Peter Pan and its 2002 sequel Return to Never Land.
Unlike Disney's two Peter Pan films featuring the character, which were produced primarily
using traditional animation, Tinker Bell was produced using digital 3D modeling.
The film was released on DVD and Blu-ray by Walt Disney
Studios Home Entertainment on October 28, 2008.
Tinker Bell is the first Disney film to feature Tinker Bell in a speaking role.
Actress Brittany Murphy was originally selected for the
part before the role went to Mae Whitman.
The film follows Tinker Bell’s origin story, before she met Peter Pan, as she works
out her place in Pixie Hollow and struggles with what her “talent” is.
The film explores themes of fairy, spring, gardening.